# Mohammad Zaatari

Lebanon, Saida, Njasa Street 35

Phone Number: +961 / 81450826 | Email: <a href="mailto:mohamadalzaatari748@gmail.com">mohamadalzaatari748@gmail.com</a> | GitHub Profile: <a href="https://github.com/taha007860">https://github.com/taha007860</a> | LinkedIn Profile: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-al-zaatari-976347240/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-al-zaatari-976347240/</a> | Portfolio Website: <a href="https://taha007860.github.io/Mohammad-Zaatari-Portfolio/">https://taha007860.github.io/Mohammad-Zaatari-Portfolio/</a>

"Know what you have to have what you want"

### **Personal Profile**

As a USAID scholar and computer scientist at the American University of Beirut, I have a passion for generating endless creative ideas and bringing them to life through deliberate and thoughtful implementation. I invest time in learning and researching to ensure the optimal execution of each project. With my technical skills in AI/ML research, software/web development, and algorithm/data structure design, I'm equipped to turn these ideas into tangible results. I'm committed to delivering high-quality work and continuously expanding my knowledge to improve and innovate. I'm excited to collaborate with others who share my enthusiasm for pushing the boundaries of what's possible.

## **Education**

### American University of Beirut (AUB)

Beirut, Lebanon

BS in Computer Science

Enrollment Date: Sept 2021 - Expected Graduation Date: 30 May 2024

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_

Amazon Web Services in partnership with American University of Beirut (AUB)

Onsite

June 2023 - September 2023

Apprenticeship

Software Engineer

- Participated in a comprehensive 3-day bootcamp hosted by Amazon engineers at the American University of Beirut, gaining
  insight into various computer science fields: Frontend Development Backend Development DevOps Machine Learning.
- Acquired knowledge in a diverse set of programming languages and technologies.
- Engaged in a 2-month industry mentorship program with Amazon software engineers.
- Collaborated on a project to develop a fashion recommendation system utilizing machine learning techniques to enhance the system's accuracy and user experience.
- Technical Skills: HTML · CSS · JavaScript · Bootstrap · React JS · Node JS · TypeScript · Amazon Dynamodb · Git · GitHub · Frontend Development · Object Oriented Programming (OOP) · Artificial Intelligence (AI) · Agile Methodologies · DevOps · Machine Learning, Flask · Amazon DevOps
- · Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Problem Solving.

#### CodSoft

#### Remote

December 2023 - January 2024

Internship

Software Developer

- Successfully developed three Python projects to fulfill internship requirements.
- Simple Calculator: Designed a user-friendly calculator for basic arithmetic operations.
- Password Generator: Created a robust tool for generating strong, secure passwords.
- Contact Book: Developed a comprehensive contact management system for storing, viewing, updating, searching and deleting contact information.
- · Technical Skills: Python (Programming Language)

### **YMY Agency**

### Remote

February 2023 - March 2023

Freelancer

Software Developer

- Developed a Repository Administration System utilizing C# programming language and delivering a tailored solution for a client's project in an academic course.
- Completed Two AppLabs with Code.org where I successfully executed two distinct projects for clients. The projects were part of their respective academic courses, showcasing practical application of skills.
- Designed a Basic Ecommerce Website employing HTML and CSS for development and creating a user-friendly site for a client's web development course assignment.
- Conducted Website Evaluation and Enhancements where I analyzed existing website designs, focusing on aesthetic appeal and

1

user experience, evaluated the clarity of website content and messaging and reviewed and revitalized client logos for brand alignment.

Technical Skills: C# · AppLab · HTML · CSS

### American University of Beirut – IT Depratment

Onsite

September 2023 - November 2023

Part-time

Assistant Business Analyst

- · Played a role in enhancing the Common Application process for the American University of Beirut.
- Integrated the application system with Slate CRM.
- Organized and managed student data using Excel files, ensuring data importation.
- Undertook research to figure out the steps of the integration process.

Technical Skills: Microsoft Excel · Slate CRM · Microsoft Word · Customer Relationship Management (CRM) · Microsoft Office · Data Analysis · Research

#### Bennette&Ranville

#### Remote

September 2023 - October 2023

Internship

Research Development Software Developer

- Conducted thorough testing of the company's website, ensuring its front-end functionality was accurately implemented in ReactJS.
- Proposed various ReactJS code snippets, aimed at enhancing the website's performance and user experience.
- · Undertook extensive research to identify potential enhancements for the website, focusing on both functionality and design.
- Collaborated effectively with the tech stack, including Fluent Bit and Docker, to develop and integrate a robust logging system for the website.

Technical Skills: ReactJS · Research · Fluent Bit · Docker · Website Manual Testing

# **Projects**

Check my portfolio of projects at this website: <a href="https://taha007860.github.io/Mohammad-Zaatari-Portfolio/">https://taha007860.github.io/Mohammad-Zaatari-Portfolio/</a> Check source codes of my projects at my GitHub profile: <a href="https://github.com/taha007860">https://github.com/taha007860</a>

# **Achievements, Awards and Certificates**

Got 780/800 on Amideast Scholastic Assessment Test Math section (SAT Math)

Got 1390/1600 on Amideast Scholastic Assessment Test (SAT)

Got First place on the American University of Beirut Library Knowledge Competition

Got Certificate "NewGen Peacebuilders" from Rotary Action Group for Peace

Got Badges, HTML/CSS/React JS/Microsoft PowerPoint skill badges with LinkedIn

Got USAID Scholarship at the American University of Beirut

Got Qatar Scholarship (Education Above All Program) at the American University of Beirut

Got 2nd place on Innovation Camp that was organized by INJAZ Lebanon

# Languages

**English** Professional proficiency **Arabic** Native proficiency **French** Elementary proficiency